I am a UX Designer who has spent the last 7 years working in various capacities in research and writing. My background working in the legal industry provides me with the experience of working in a fast-paced environment, while my practical understanding of front-end development allows me to operate concurrently with developers in agile or lean frameworks to effectively execute design sprints.

#### Skills

#### **UX Skills:**

A/B Testing, Ethnographic/User Research, C&C Analysis, Card Sorting, Contextual Inquiry, E-Commerce, Heuristic Evaluation, Information Architecture, Journey Mapping, Personas, SWOT Analysis, User Scenarios, Wireframes

#### **UI Skills:**

Branding, Logo/Icon Design, Modular Design, Prototyping, Sketching, User-Centered Design, Web & Mobile Design (Adaptive & Responsive Web)

#### Tools:

Adobe CC (XD, Illustrator, PhotoShop), Figma, Invision, Jira, Marvel, MS Office, Shopify, Sketch, Zeplin

## **Professional Experience**

(Freelance) Dec. 2018 – Present

## **UX/UI** Designer | Researcher

Work with a variety of clients and their teams to conduct research, validate, and develop all design elements, ranging from product to interface.

- Responsible for design, wireframes, prototyping, documentation, and iteration.
- Constant collaboration with stakeholders and developers to ensure that goals are met with quality.

ConFreaks & Geeks Oct. 2017 - Present

#### Associate Editor | Interviewer | Community Manager | UX/UI Designer

ConFreaks & Geeks is a digital and gaming media company that provides coverage of conventions spanning the western United States, in-depth reviews, and community engagement.

- Author op-ed pieces, video game reviews, and features for 9,000 unique subscribers.
- Research and prepare for interviews with community icons and award-winning cosplayers.
- Researched and designed scalable content management system for web and mobile sites.

Distillery Oct. 2018 - Nov. 2018

## **UX Designer**

Distillery is a full-service software development company recognized for their work in large-scale enterprises as well as mobile applications spanning areas such as finance, lifestyle, and gaming.

Conducted C&C analyses with competitors as well as businesses utilizing similar software.



Los Angeles, CA | www.nicolendoan.com | <u>doan.nicole@gmail.com</u> | (408) 857-6390

- Prepared and led user interviews during 1-week user research sprint.
- Conducted open card sorts to inform information architecture and hierarchy.
- Created PowerPoint presentations for weekly check-ins with client.
- Created a product site map and 3 user flows identifying the needs of each different user type.
- Created mid-fidelity wireframes to present to client and to assist UI designer with the creation of a style sheet.

# Jobs for Hope (a Hack for LA project) UX/UI Designer | Researcher

Jul. 2018 - Nov. 2018

'Jobs for Hope' is an open source civic project working to streamline the usability and search experience of skilled individuals seeking jobs through the Los Angeles County Homeless Initiative.

- Worked alongside developers to determine build limitations and execution strategies in preparation for 2-week design sprint.
- Conducted usability tests of current site to identify user pain points when searching for a job as a 'Manager' and synthesizing test results with other UX researchers to inform feature prioritization.
- Created a high-fidelity wireframe and prototype to be presented to a director of the Los Angeles
   County Homeless Initiative to receive clearance to move forward with the project and development.
- Conducted a design studio to design a hexagonal badge/sticker to represent the Jobs for Hope project in the 2018 National Day of Civic Hacking.

Grid110 Aug. 2018 - Sep. 2018

#### UX Designer | Researcher

Grid110 is an economic and community-development accelerator program partnered with the Los Angeles Mayor's Office.

- Conducted C&C Analyses of existing database software and social platforms.
- Conducted user surveys to capture users who were unable to participate in user interviews.
- Conducted user interviews of Grid110 users over a 3-day research sprint.
- Synthesized response data to create a feature prioritization, user personas, and user flows.
- Created a paper prototype to conduct usability tests to validate initial assumptions.
- Created a high-fidelity prototype to showcase a web-based user interface.

#### Education

## **General Assembly, Downtown Los Angeles**

Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Certificate of Completion in UX Design, Research, Strategy

#### **University of California, Los Angeles**

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology, Specialization in Sociocultural Studies

#### Pasadena City College

Jun. 2007 - Jun. 2013

Associate of Arts in Social Sciences, Specialization in Anthropology

Associate of Sciences in Paralegal Studies, Specialization in Legal Research (Certified)